それじゃ　離すぜ…。
Gon-kun! Where is everyone?
うわ!!　待て待て！ 起きてる！　起きてるよ!!
You need more rest, Gon-kun...
うぅ…。 でも　これで そっちのチップは残り２０時間。
Some x Brother x Trouble
だが　勝負自体は　２勝１敗で こっちがリーチだ。
After Gon learned why Killua
had been disqualified, he was furious with Gittarackur...
さぁ　次は　そっちの番だ！
Rather, Killua's brother, Illumi.
４戦目の勝負は 時間をチップ代わりにした賭け 次なる問題は…
Apologize to Killua!
さぁ　次の賭けの問題を 出してもらおうか。
Apologize? For what?
それとも　浅知恵がバレて おじけづいたか？
You don't know what you did wrong? Nope.
ウフっ　いいわ。
You don't have the right to be his brother.
おぉ！ な…　何だよ　めちゃくちゃ かわいいじゃねえか。
Must I earn the right to be his brother?
嫌な予感がする。 それじゃあ　次は 私が男か女かを賭けてもらうわ。
He doesn't need to earn the
right to be my friend!
いや…。 こいつ　どう見ても女だろ
This boy is...
まさか　オカマちゃんか？
Don't bother apologizing.
いやいや　どう見ても女だ
Just take me to see Killua. What will you do then?
うん。
That should be obvious...
構わねえけどよ
I'm gonna rescue Killua!
もし　俺が外れた場合 どうやって　それを証明する気だ？
You make it sound as
though I kidnapped him...
そうねぇ　あなたの気の済むまで 存分に調べてもらっていいわ。
He walked away on his own.
この　私の体をね。
But it wasn't by choice.
え！　体を!?
He was being manipulated by you people.
オホホ…　おぉ。
It's the same thing as kidnapping him!
よし　決めた 「男」のほうに１０時間　賭ける！
We happened to be discussing
this very subject, Gon.
フッ。 やっぱり。 あのスケベおやじ！
Kurapika and Leorio have both
lodged complaints.
えっ　何で分かったの？
The committee has been discussing
これなら仮に外れて 女だったとしても
the fairness of Killua's disqualification. Killua had been behaving
思う存分　調べることができる！
in a strange manner during and
since his battle with the man
当たっても　外れても 俺にとって　おいしい選択 てか　外れろ
who called himself Gittarackur! I believe that he was hypnotized
into committing murder.
…ということだ。 なるほどね。 さぁ　答えてもらおうか！
Under normal circumstances, it would be impossible to use
hypnosis to induce a person to kill.
残念ねぇ　私は女よ。 そっ　それは本当か？
However, as Killua was raised
in a family of assassins, murder was a part of his daily life, so it's natural that he would lack
the ethical restraint of most!
じゃあ　確かめてみる？
I want to mention that the attack happened during the
match between Bodoro and me.
ももも…　もちろんだとも！
It's possible that he was trying to help me.
アハハ！　アハハハ…。
Given that, the one who should be disqualified is me.
外れて悔いなし
In any case, Killua was not in control of his own actions.
ああ。 見るに堪えない光景だったな。
Thus, he should not have been disqualified!
あいつ　負けるな。 えっ？
That is mere speculation.
敵は　レオリオの 勝負傾向を読んでるぜ。
There is no proof.
あいつは　外れても　なるべく ダメージを受けないように 賭けている。
There were no clear signs of manipulation.
賭け事では 負けた時のことを考えてる奴は
In fact, I would question
いつまでも勝てねえもんなのさ。
the claim that he was hypnotized.
レオリオには　まるっきり ギャンブルの才能が　ねえってことだ。
I agree that the incident occurred after the battle between Leorio
and Bodoro had begun.
読み通りね あいつの賭け方には 全く怖さが　ない
At that point, both fighters
were evenly matched.
そのやり方じゃ　何べんやっても 私には勝てないわよ フッ。
Bodoro had more experience. But in terms of raw combat ability,
Leorio was the stronger.
何を賭ける？ ハッ。
There was no need for Killua to interfere.
残りのチップは １０時間だけか
Like when you fought Hisoka.
レオリオには　もう後が　ない。 もし　次の賭けに負ければ ２勝２敗のタイ。
Back then, what did he say to you? Neither of you seemed particularly tired.
その上　負けた分の５０時間 タワー脱出のリミットが短くなる。
But Hisoka whispered something in your ear, right before conceding.
レオリオ…。
That's pretty strange.
もう負けられねえが 確実に勝てる問題なんて すぐには浮かばねえし。
I'd understand surrendering after your
opponent whispers something to you, as happened with Hanzo and me,
or Bodoro and Hisoka.
あっ　そうだ！ 今度は　俺が男か女かを 賭けるってのは　どうだ？
Because we were under
considerable pressure.
いやいや　そいつは やっぱり無理があるよな。 おいおい　おっさん！ さっきから心の声が丸聞こえだぜ。
But in your case, the exact opposite happened. I have to wonder if you struck
some sort of bargain.
そうだ！ レオリオ！ あ？
If you're going to question
anything that seems odd, your own victory was quite odd, indeed.
レオリオが１０歳代かどうか っていうのを賭けてみたら？ おい　こら！　ゴン！
If you have nothing to hide,
you should tell us what he said.
俺は　そんな問題になるほど 老けちゃいねえぞ！
Right now.
どう見たって１０歳代だ！
I have no obligation to tell you.
じゅ…　１０歳代!?
Maybe not, but I believe you owe it to us.
どう見ても　おっさん。
Not really.
よし！ こうなったら　ジャンケンだ！ ジャンケンで　どっちが勝つか 賭けようぜ！
If you consider my victory to be odd, a victory by default would be equally odd.
フフフ…　いいわよ。
What?!
ジャンケンか　また難しいものを 持ち出して来たな。 えっ？　ジャンケンって そんなに難しい？
None of that matters...
フッ　何を隠そうジャンケンには ちょっと自信があるのよ
Come on... I want to get this lecture
over with so I can leave.
この前やった 商店街のジャンケン大会でも
Hey, now...
グルメ旅行をゲットしたしな そうねぇ　じゃあ　私は
None of that matters!
自分が勝つほうに ８０時間　賭けるわ。
It's pointless to argue over whether
someone should have passed.
はっ　８０時間!? 別に問題ないでしょ 賭ける時間は私の自由よ。
If you aren't happy about passing, keep working until you're satisfied.
なっ…　まぁ　それは　そうだが。
If Killua retakes the Hunter Exam,
he'll definitely pass!
それに　もし　あなたが負けても 取られる時間は １０時間だけだから　安心して。
It's unfortunate that he failed this time,
but it is what it is.
８０時間も賭けなくたって １０時間で十分だろ 負けたら　どうすんだ？ それとも　それだけ 自信があるってことか？
What does matter... If you've been forcing Killua to kill,
against his will, all this time, I'll make you pay!
思った通り やっぱり　うろたえてるわね
Make me pay?
ウフフ…　ホントに 分かりやすい男だこと
What, exactly, will you do? I won't do anything.
ジャンケンは ルール自体は単純だが
Only, once I rescue Killua,
I'll never let you see him again!
しかし　相手に心理を読まれ コントロールされてしまうと
Ahem.
負ける確率は　ぐんと上がる。 つまり　単純頭のレオリオには
Is everyone finished?
ジャンケンは 不利なゲームってことになる。
Gon is absolutely correct.
なるほど。 よし！　決めたぜ！
You must decide for yourselves
if you were worthy of passing.
ウッフフ…。 何だよ？
You may complain about
the results all you like, but we will not be changing our minds.
あなたの出す　てが 手に取るように分かるわ。
Killua has been disqualified.
えっ。 私は　ひとの心が読めるのよ。 ウソつけ！　ハッタリかまして 俺を動揺させようたって
And the rest of you have passed the exam.
むぅ…。 ウフっ
Okay, then I shall continue the orientation.
案の定　根拠のないウソでも 動揺してるわ ひとの心が読めるだと？ ウソだ　ウソに決まってる
The cards I've passed out
are your Hunter Licenses. This card allows you
でも　もし ホントだとしたら… レオリオはグを出す。 えっ？ 行くわよ。 あぁ！
to enter 90% of the countries
that limit immigration, as well as 75% of the restricted
areas in the world.
ジャン　ケン…。
Crazy...
ポン！ フゥ。 ホントだ　よく分かったね。 緊張している人間は 開くという行為を
This card also provides free access
to 95% of public facilities, and a line of credit that rivals
large corporations.
無意識に避ける傾向がある。
If you sell the card, you'll have enough
money to last seven lifetimes.
つまり　彼女は　わざと レオリオを動揺させて パを出しにくくさせた。
And if you keep it, you'll still
be living in comfort.
そうすれば　グさえ出しときゃ 勝ちか　あいこに 持ち込めるもんな。
So take extra care that your
license isn't lost or stolen.
いっただろ ジャンケンは結局　心理戦なんだ。
You won't receive a replacement.
なるほど。
According to our estimates,
one in five Hunters
ん？　待てよ？ 今　俺もお前も グを出して　あいこだったよな？
lose their card within a year of receiving it.
それが　どうしたの？ ほれ　見ろ！ やっぱり　ひとの心が読めるなんて ウソじゃねえか！
As a Hunter, your first challenge
is to protect your card.
俺の心が読めてたら 勝てたはずだよな　え？
The rest is up to you.
ウフフ…。 なっ　何が　おかしい！
Rise above challenges,
believe in your own strength, and fulfill your dreams.
わざと　あいこにしたに 決まってるじゃない。 ウソつけ！ 忘れてないかしら？ 時間稼ぎも 私達にとって重要なのよ。
Then, we now declare the seven members
here to be new Hunters!
あいこを出し続けることだって 可能なんだから。 うっ。 でも　そんな　つまんないこと 続けてても飽きるだけ。
Hunter Vocabulary
次で決めてあげるわ！
License
考えて！　ほら　ウフフフ…。
Gittarackur...
悩み　迷い。
Tell me where Killua is.
自信をなくした者は 心理的に安定を望もうとする。
Are you really going to take him away? I think that's a bad idea.
そして　前と同じてを出すか 自信を回復しようとして
I don't care what you think! Killua is my friend.
前のてより強いてを 出そうとするんだ。
I'm taking him with me.
つまり　あの女
Do they feel the same way?
次にレオリオに　グか　パを 出させようとしてるってわけだ。
You bet.
そう　だから　彼女は パを出せば負けは　ない。
Fine.
じゃあ　レオリオは その裏をかけばいいんだね！
I doubt you'll be able to
make it there anyway.
まぁ　冷静に判断できれば そういうことだが…。
Killua went home. Home?
レオリオ。 何だ？
Kukuroo Mountain.
あのさぁ 次は　チョキを出せば勝てるよ。
Our family lives at the very top.
あ？　チョキ？
Kukuroo Mountain?
ウフっ　出せば？　チョキ。
Got it. Thanks.
んなこと　いって 自分はグを出すつもりだろ
Is it really okay
いや　その裏をかいて パを出すつもりか？
for an assassin to give away
his base of operations?
いやいや　さらに その裏をかいてチョキ
Sure, it isn't a secret or anything. The locals all know where we live.
いやいやいや さらに　その裏をかいてグ
Well, I'm sure they'll see the
light once they arrive.
ンガ！　もう分かんねえ！ 行くわよ！ えっ。
We live in completely different worlds...
あいこで…。 しょ！
Oh, this? Yep, it's broken.
アッハハハ…！　私の勝ち。
He has incredible potential.
くっ。 アッハハハ…！
I can understand why you want
to see him grow up.
ジャンケンって奥が深いんだね。 これで２勝２敗か。 しかも　賭けに負けた分のチップ
Didn't I tell you? But that makes him all the more dangerous.
５０時間を 支払わなければならない。
This would be the best chance to...
すまねえ　ジャンケンには 自信があったんだが…。
Gon is my prey.
フン　あのザマでか？ 何だと!?　チッ。
Touch him, and you'll suffer
the consequences. I know.
今回は　何も 言い返さないでおいてやるぜ。
I've only known you for a short while,
but I know your tastes.
ねぇ　彼らの今の残りタイムって どれくらいかな？
What are you going to do now? Wait patiently.
５９時間４５分だ。 [ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　つまり 彼らに残された時間は
For the fruit to ripen...
実質　１０時間を 切ってるというわけだな。
Kukuroo Mountain?
残り時間なんて関係ない。
Never heard of it before.
ゲッ。 ハッ。
Kurapika, do you know where it is?
なぜなら　俺の相手は 死ぬしかないのだから。
Hey, Kurapika! Huh? Oh, what is it?
いよいよ　最後の勝負だ。
It was a short, yet seemingly long
acquaintance, but I had fun. So did I.
んじゃ　行って来るぜ。 えっ　キルア!?
If you ever visit my country, let me know.
何だよ　それ。 しまった！
I can show you the best tourist spots!
どうしても俺で　勝っておかなきゃ ダメだったんだ！
See ya!
ゴン　こいつ　すげぇムカつくぞ！ まぁまぁ。
Bye!
どんな勝負になるか
Cloud-Hidden Ninja
Hanzo
分かんないうちから 諦めんなよな。 そりゃ　暗算対決とかいわれたら お手上げだけどさ。
A shinobi who tries to leave an impression... Hey.
そうか！　相手次第じゃ まだ　チャンスは あるってことだよな！
Sorry about getting so excited back there.
最後は　あの小坊ずか。
No, I also lost control.
奴の餌食になっちまうとはな。 かわいそう　まだ若いのに。
Forgive me. No, I only got mad because you were right.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　できれば 私も彼を使いたくはなかった。
I was using you to take out my
frustration for winning by default.
しかし ハンター試験に情けは無用。
But I'm over that now.
ここで果てるなら それもまた運命ということだ。 [ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　手錠を外すぞ。
Since I passed, I'm going to make the best of it! The question is what to do next. Yes, you're right.
あ…。
and discovering new species,
as an Exotic Game Hunter.
え…。
An Exotic Game Hunter...
フン！ みんな　ビビり過ぎじゃねえの？
You can use this to obtain
all kinds of information.
バカ　やめろ！
Is there anything you'd like to know?
そんなに怖がるほどの奴か？ しょせん　昔の話…。
I can look it up on the spot. Oh... Can you look up a Hunter named Ging?
あぁ…！
Ging Freecss.
あっ。
Huh? Really?
あいつは…。 知ってるの？
Forget it, then...
俺達の負けでいい。 キルア！　あいつとは戦うな！
Looks like your dad is someone really special.
何で？ バラシ屋ジョネス
Okay, let me know if anything comes up. This is my e-mail address.
ザバン市史上最悪の 大量殺人犯だ。
Bye. Bye!
老若男女問わず　１４６人が
We should have asked him to
look up Kukuroo Mountain.
彼の手によって 無残な死を遂げた有名な事件さ。 その遺体　全てには 共通項があった。
That's right. It's okay. As Chairman Netero was saying,
we are all Hunters now.
どの殺人も　全て 素手によって行われていたんだ。
It's a bad idea to let other Hunters
know what you're doing. We can look it up ourselves.
あいつの特長は その異常なまでの握力
Gon-kun.
指の力！
Satotz-san!
あんな異常殺人鬼の相手を することは　ねえ！
Gon-kun, you forgot this. Oh, right... Thanks!
試験は　今年だけじゃないからな！
And do you have a moment?
あっ　おい　キルア！
We'll be waiting in the lobby.
ったく　あいつ　俺の話 ちゃんと聞いてたのかよ！ 彼に任せよう 何か考えがあるのかもしれない。
Forgive me, but I couldn't help but
overhear your conversation. I happen to specialize in the
discovery, restoration, and preservation of ancient ruins.
勝負の方法は？ 勝負？　勘違いするな。
But after watching a certain Hunter at work, I came to feel ashamed.
これから行われるのは 一方的な惨殺さ。 試験も恩赦も　俺には興味がない。 お前は　ただ 泣き叫んでいればいい。 そう　ＯＫ。 じゃあ 死んだほうが負けでいいね。 ああ　そういうことだ。
That Hunter would discover ruins, spend his own money to
completely restore them, and take steps to preserve the
ruins for future generations, thus ensuring that ordinary people
would have a chance to see them. I was more impressed by
his dedication to his job
お前の亡きがらは 俺様が　この手でバラバラに…。
than by the beauty of the ruins. The work he did to preserve those ruins
あぁ！ あっ！
has been documented in manuals
used around the world.
うぅ…。
And this Hunter, Gon-kun, was Ging Freecss, the man
you were asking about.
あ…　何だ？　何だか寒い。
I wished to meet him, so I did some investigating.
それ…　お　俺の…？
I wasn't able to learn anything about him... Really? Figures.
か…　返して…。
My goal is to become a Hunter like him. My dream is to thank him in person one day.
うぅ…　あぁ…。
Uh-huh.
さて　これで　３勝２敗 ここはパスだろ？
Oh, never mind... Take care of yourself.
ああ　君達の勝ちだ。
Yeah. You, too.
ところで おっさんは何もしてないから
Bye!
やめておく。
First, let's look up Kukuroo Mountain. Yeah.
あっそ。
Kukuroo Mountain...
あいつ　一体　何者なんだ？
"Kukuroo Mountain.
そっか　知らないんだね。 えっ　何を？
A 3,722 meter-high mountain, in the Dentora region of
the Republic of Padokea."
キルアってさ 暗殺一家のエリートなんだって。
The Republic of Padokea? Never heard of it.
えっ　暗殺一家のエリート!?
Where is it? Hold on.
ただいま。 ぐっ。
I'll bring up a map.
何？ いや　その…
This is the Republic of Padokea.
お疲れさまです。
It should be fine.
It appears to be a stable country.
そこを通り過ぎると 小さな部屋がある
When do we leave? Today! Right now! Yeah, no objection from me!
そこで賭けに負けた分の ５０時間を過ごしてもらおう。
Understood. Then, I'll order tickets.
君は　すでに ゴールしていると思ったよ。
Yahoo!
一番乗りだぜぇ！　あれ？ [ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　第３号　２９４番ハンゾー。
Hey, Gon!
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　１２時間３分。 ぬわぁ！
Do you realize how far away the airport is?
何てこった！　３番目かよ。
I want to rescue Killua as soon
as humanly possible!
やれやれ　これから５０時間も
Fine, you win.
この部屋で 過ごさなきゃなんねえのかよ。 キルア。 あ？
This reminds me of the Hunter Exam. That's right.
さっきの技は　どうやったんだ？ さっきの技？ 相手の心臓を 瞬時に奪っただろう？
This is nothing compared
to the Hunter Exam.
あぁ　あれ？ 技ってほどのもんじゃ　ないよ。
Yeah...
ただ抜き取っただけだ。 抜き取った？
You got that right.
自分の肉体を操作して 盗みやすくしたけど。
Okay... Race you to the airport!
つっ　爪が…。 すご！
Ready...
殺人鬼なんていっても 結局　アマチュアじゃん。
Go!
俺　一応　元プロだし。
Gon and his friends set off for
the Republic of Padokea.
でも　親父は もっと　うまく盗むぜ。 抜き取る時 血が一滴も出ないからね。
Their destination is Kukuroo Mountain,
where Killua's home is located.
さてと　あと丸２日以上あるぜ。
Satotz.
どうする？　キルア。
Menchi. Buhara.
まずは 暇をつぶせるものがないか
Hey, Satotz...
部屋ん中　探してみようぜ。 うん！
That was a close call. You were watching?
ったく　子供は気楽でいいぜ。
That boy is a mystery...
よいしょっと。
I find myself wanting to help him.
３勝２敗で勝利したものの
I almost let the cat out of the bag.
５０時間のペナルティーを
About how the real Hunter Exam
この小部屋で過ごすことになった ゴン達５人
hasn't ended yet.